Persico, Joseph; Papers apap030
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Writings, ca. 1930s-2001; 2; 18.23 cubic ft.
  - Piercing the Reich, 1940-1979; 2.1; 1.4 cubic ft.
    - Piercing the Reich, 1970s. FBI Declassified Files, 1940s-1970s; 2.1.1
      - Turnball, William (Box 27 (2.1.1-Piercing the Reich), Folder 84)
      - Ulmer (Box 27 (2.1.1-Piercing the Reich), Folder 85)
      - Ulsamer, Edgar (Box 27 (2.1.1-Piercing the Reich), Folder 86)
      - Van Arkel, Gerheart (Box 28 (2.1.1-Piercing the Reich), Folder 1)
      - Van Dyke, Orpha (Box 28 (2.1.1-Piercing the Reich), Folder 2)
      - Viertel, Peter (Box 28 (2.1.1-Piercing the Reich), Folder 3)
      - Vuj Novich, George (Box 28 (2.1.1-Piercing the Reich), Folder 4)
      - Watt, Richard (Box 28 (2.1.1-Piercing the Reich), Folder 5)
      - Wynberg, Hans (Box 28 (2.1.1-Piercing the Reich), Folder 6)
      - Yovel (Box 28 (2.1.1-Piercing the Reich), Folder 7)
    - Piercing the Reich, 1976 (Box 28 (2-Publications), Folder 8-13)
      OSS War Report (July 1949, reprinted 1976).
    - Piercing the Reich, 1976 (Box 28 (2-Publications), Folder 8-13)
      OSS Operations in Europe, Africa, & the Mid-East, 1944-1945.
    - Piercing the Reich, Miscellaneous, 1976-1979 (Box 28 (2-Publications), Folder 14)
    - Piercing the Reich: American Spies in Nazi Germany, History Channel Documentary, 1976-1997 (Box 28 (2-Publications), Folder 15)
  - Columbus, ca. 1980-1990; 2.2; 0.4 cubic ft.
    The Columbus subseries includes Persico's research material, a book draft, and scripts and related material for theatrical performances.
    - Novel drafts (Box 29 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
    - Research (Box 29 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
    - Scripts & Performances (Box 29 (2-Publications), Folder 3-4)
    - Theater Voices Presentation (Box 29 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
  - My Enemy, My Brother, 1977; 2.3; 1 folder
    The subseries for My Enemy, My Brother contains only book reviews for Persico's first book.
    - My Enemy, My Brother. Book Reviews, 1977 (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
  - The Spiderweb, 1975-1983; 2.4; 1 folder
    - The Spiderweb. Miscellaneous, 1979-1983 (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
  - Edward R. Murrow: An American Original, 1984-2001; 2.5; 0.2 cubic ft.
    The Edward R. Murrow subseries includes administrative files, news clippings, material related to the promotion of the book, and correspondence about Persico's sale of rights to the book to filmmakers. Note that Persico donated most of his records related to this book to the Edward R. Murrow Center of Public Diplomacy at Tufts University.
    - Administrative, 1984-1991 (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
    - News Clippings, 1988 (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
    - Promotion, 1988 (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
    - Movie Rights, 1997-2001 (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 5A)
  - Casey: From the OSS to the CIA, 1989-1991; 2.6; 0.5 cubic ft.
    The Casey subseries includes the author's research material and drafts of the biography of William Casey. According to Publishers Weekly, Persico worked from interviews and had exclusive access to Casey's papers. All of William Casy papers were returned to his widow, Sophia Casey.
    - Administrative Files, 1990s (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 6)
    - Biography, News Clippings, Promotion, 1990s (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 7)
    - Report, 1945 (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 8)
    - Promotion, 1987-1992 (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 9)
    - Casey-Sophia Issue, 1987-1991 (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 10)
    - Draft (1-134) (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 11)
    - Draft (135-290) (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 12)
    - Draft (291-475) (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 13)
    - Draft (476-700) (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 14)
    - Draft (701-866) (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 15)
    - Draft (867-1039) (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 16)
    - Draft (1040-end) (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 17)
  - Teacher, 1989-1990; 2.7; 0.1 cubic ft.
    - Teacher, TV Script, 1989-1990; Undated (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 18)
      Research, Notes, and Administrative.
    - Teacher, TV Script, 1990 (Box 30 (2-Publications), Folder 19)
      Drafts.
  - The Imperial Rockefeller, ca. 1970s-1985; 2.8; 0.4 cubic ft.
    - Drafts (early), Undated (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
    - Drafts, Undated (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
    - Drafts (with correspondence), early 1980s-1983 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
    - Reviews, 1982 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
    - Interview Files. Interview List, 1978 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
    - Interview Files. Albright, H., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 6)
    - Interview Files. Anbinder, P., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 7)
    - Interview Files. Armao, R., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 8)
    - Interview Files. Boyd, J., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 9)
    - Interview Files. Braun, T., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 10)
    - Interview Files. Canfield, S., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 11)
    - Interview Files. Cannon, J., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 12)
    - Interview Files. Canzeri, J., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 13)
    - Interview Files. Douglass, 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 14)
    - Interview Files. Dunham, D., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 15)
    - Interview Files. Ekhof, W., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 16)
    - Interview Files. Hinman, G., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 17)
    - Interview Files. Hughes, E., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 18)
    - Interview Files. Humphries, G., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 19)
    - Interview Files. Hurd, T., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 20)
    - Interview Files. Lanigan, C., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 21)
    - Interview Files. Lelyveld, 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 22)
    - Interview Files. Logue, E., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 23)
    - Interview Files. Marshall, A., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 24)
    - Interview Files. Morrow, 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 25)
    - Interview Files. Rosenbaum, 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 26)
    - Interview Files. Spad, 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 27)
    - Interview Files. Wallison, P., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 28)
    - Interview Files. Watts, 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 29)
    - Interview Files. Whiteman, 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 30)
    - Interview Files. Whitman, 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 31)
    - Interview Files. Wilson, 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 32)
    - Interview Files. Zinker, L., 1978-1979 (Box 31 (2-Publications), Folder 33)
  - Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial, ca. 1930-2001; 2.9; 3 cubic ft. 2 films
    The Nuremberg subseries includes the author's research material, manuscript drafts, correspondence, and promotion for each of the book's editions. Material related to the History Channel documentary Nuremberg: Tyranny on Trial and the TNT television miniseries Nuremberg is also included in this subseries. Note that material related to Persico's promotion of both TNT's Nuremberg and the reissued paperback edition of the book are included in the folder of promotional records for 2000-2001. The Writings subseries includes scripts for the History Channel documentaries "Piercing the Reich: The Deadly Deceivers" and "Nuremberg: Tyranny on Trial" in the "Documentaries, Narration" folder.
    - Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial, 1930s-1995; 2.9.1
      - American Heritage Article, 1992-1994 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 1)
      - Air Raid, 1945-1990s (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, 1979-1994 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 3)
      - US Army History Institute (Carlisle, PA), 1991-1994 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 4)
      - Research Materials, mostly 1940s (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 5)
      - Nuremberg Chronology, 1937-1946 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 6)
      - Clearances, 1991-1993 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 7)
      - Dimensions, (a Journal of Holocaust Studies), 1993-1994 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 8)
      - Directions, undated (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 9)
      - Nuremberg Directory, printed 1991 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 10)
      - Pamphlets (Holocaust Museum & Memorial Council), 1990s (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 11)
      - Interview notes, 1991 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 12)
      - Military History Quarterly, 1993-1994 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 13)
      - National Archives Docs (Records of War Crimes Trial Interrogations & Trial Proceedings), 1945-1949 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 14)
      - Photos (of the trial and the Holocaust), 1940s (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 15)
      - Photo credits, orders, & book cover, 1940s-1993 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 16)
      - Book Proposal, "Last Day at Nuremberg", undated (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 17)
      - Reunion materials, 1991 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 18)
      - FDR Library materials, 1990s (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 19)
      - Sources, ca. 1980s-1990s (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 20)
      - Syracuse University Library Information, 1990s (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 21)
      - Notes, 1992 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 22)
      - Nuremberg Trial Telephone Directory, 1945 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 23)
      - Titles, undated (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 24)
      - Nuremberg Tourism Pamphlets, ca. 1980s-1990s (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 25)
      - Trip folder, Washington, D.C., undated (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 26)
      - Viking-Penguin (Publishing Co.), Correspondence and Notes, 1990-1993 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 27)
      - Yad Vashem Research, 1991 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 28)
      - Research and Notes, 1940s-1990s; 6 folders (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 29-31)
      - Nuremberg Reunion, 1995 (two years after the book's release) (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 32)
      - Nuremberg: Tyranny on Trial, History Channel Documentary, 1995 (Box 32 (2.9.1-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 33)
    - Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial, early 1990s; 2.9.2
      - Draft 1 Copy (1-165), early 1990s (Box 33 (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 1)
      - Draft 1 Copy (166-386), early 1990s (Box 33 (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 2)
      - Draft 1 Copy (387-574), early 1990s (Box 33 (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 3)
      - Draft 1 Copy (575-748), early 1990s (Box 33 (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 4)
      - Draft 1 Copy (749-end), early 1990s (Box 33 (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 5)
      - Draft 1, 2nd Edit (1-188), early 1990s (Box 33 (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 6)
      - Draft 1, 2nd Edit (189-324), early 1990s (Box 33A (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 1)
      - Draft 1, 2nd Edit (325-500), early 1990s (Box 33A (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 2)
      - Draft 1, 2nd Edit (501-674), early 1990s (Box 33A (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 3)
      - Draft 1, 2nd Edit (675-end), early 1990s (Box 33A (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 4)
      - Draft unspecified (1-136), early 1990s (Box 33A (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 5)
      - Draft unspecified (137-327), early 1990s (Box 33A (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 6)
      - Draft unspecified (328-511), early 1990s (Box 33B (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 1)
      - Draft unspecified (512-645), early 1990s (Box 33B (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 2)
      - Draft unspecified (646-end), early 1990s (Box 33B (2.9.2-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 3)
    - Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial, 1993; 2.9.3
      - Photos of the Holocaust & the Nuremberg Trial, ca. early 1940s-1946 (Box 33C (2.9.3-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 1)
      - Draft II (pgs 1-101) (Box 33C (2.9.3-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 2)
      - Draft II (pgs 101-200) (Box 33C (2.9.3-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 3)
      - Draft II (pgs 201-300) (Box 33C (2.9.3-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 4)
      - Draft II (pgs 301-400) (Box 33C (2.9.3-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 5)
      - Draft II (pgs 401-500) (Box 33C (2.9.3-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial))
      - Draft II (pgs 501-600) (Box 33C (2.9.3-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 7)
      - Draft II (pgs 601-700) (Box 33C (2.9.3-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 8)
      - Draft II (pgs 701-783) (Box 33C (2.9.3-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 9)
    - Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial, ca. 1930-2001; 2.9.4
      - Book Reviews, 1994 (Box 42 (2.9.4-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1991-1999 (Box 42 (2.9.4-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 2)
      - Film, Photographs, 1999 (Box 42 (2.9.4-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 3)
      - Film, Production, 1993-2000 (Box 42 (2.9.4-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 4)
      - Manuscript Editing, 1993-1994 (Box 42 (2.9.4-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 5)
      - Promotion, 1993-1995 (Box 42 (2.9.4-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 6)
      - Promotion, 2000-2001 (Box 42 (2.9.4-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 7)
      - Screenplay Notes, ca. 1995 (Box 42 (2.9.4-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 8)
      - Shooting Script, 1999 July 20 (Box 42 (2.9.4-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 9)
      - Thomas F. Leahy Panel, 1999 (Box 43 (2.9.4-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 1)
      - Unidentified Nuremberg War Crimes Trial Book, undated (Box 43 (2.9.4-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 2)
      - War Crimes, News Clippings, 1993-1995 (Box 43 (2.9.4-Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial), Folder 3)
    - Nuremberg, TNT Television Movie, Based on Nuremberg: Infamy on Trial, VHS, 2000 July 16
    - Joseph E. Persico on the Liz Bishop Show discussing Nuremberg, VHS, 2000 July 16
  - Roosevelt's Secret War: FDR and World War II Espionage, 2001; 2.10; 0.2 cubic ft.
    This subseries includes a review of Roosevelt's Secret War: FDR and World War II Espionage from The New York Times Book Review. Artwork for the review by Thomas Powers was featured on the cover of the issue.
    - Roosevelt's Secret War: FDR and World War II Espionage, Book Review, The New York Times Book Review, 2001 (Box 48 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
- Speeches and Writings, 1958-2003; 3; 1.17 cubic ft.
  The texts, drafts, news clippings, correspondence, and other supporting material is available for speeches and other non-book writings of Persico.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Speeches, 1975-2002; 3.1; 0.17 cubic ft.
    The texts, drafts, news clippings, correspondence, and other supporting material is available for some of the speeches and lectures given by Persico. Also included in this subseries is material related to panels Persico participated in on topics related to his publications. Note that additional material related to Persico's speeches is available in the Correspondence series as the creator did not always separately file that correspondence.
    - American Swiss Foundation, Speaking Engagement, Correspondence, 1997-2001 (Box 44 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 1)
    - Commencement Address, Gloversville High School, Gloversville, NY, 1975 (Box 44 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 2)
    - Commencement Address, University at Albany, SUNY, Albany, NY, 1996 (Box 44 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 3)
    - Dartmouth, Montgomery Fellows Lecture, Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 44 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 4)
    - Greek Public Television ERT, Program about Colin Powell, Correspondence, 2002 (Box 44 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 5)
    - Harry S. Truman Presidential Library, Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 44 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 6)
    - The Rockefellers, American Experience Television Documentary, 1998-2000 (Box 44 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 7)
    - Speakers Project, 1995 (Box 44 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 8)
    - Speaking Engagements, 1991-2002 (Box 44 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 9)
    - University at Albany Veterans Project, 2001 (Box 44 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 10)
  - Writings, 1958-2003; 3.2; 1 cubic foot
    The Writings subseries includes drafts, news clippings, correspondence, and other supporting material available for the non-book writings of Persico. Persico has published many articles on historical topics in publications such as American Heritage as well as book reviews and opinion ("op-ed") pieces for newspapers. A few folders of research material are also included in this series. Also included in this subseries is research material assembled for writing projects that did not result in a publication of a book and an unpublished manuscript for a novel, The Fornix. The "Documentaries, Narration" folder also includes scripts for the History Channel documentaries "Piercing the Reich: The Deadly Deceivers" and "Nuremberg: Tyranny on Trial".
    - Benjamin Franklin, Research Material, ca. 2002 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 1)
    - Bogliasco Foundation Residency, 1997-2002 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 2)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, Armand Hammer: The Untold Story, "Lonely at the Top", 1996 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 3)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, Battleground Berlin: CIA vs. KGB in the Cold War, 1997 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 4)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, The Haunted Wood: Soviet Espionage in America- Stalin Era, "The Kremlin Connection", 1998-1999 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 5)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, The Sword and the Shield, "Secrets from the Lubyanka", 1999 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 6)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, The Private Life of Kim Philby: The Moscow Years, "Out in the Cold", 2000 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 7)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, A Convenient Spy: Wen Ho Lee and the Politics of Nuclear Espionage and My Country Versus Me: The First-Hand Account by the Los Alamos Scientist Who was Falsely Accused of Being a Spy, 2002 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 8)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, Intelligence in War: Knowledge of the Enemy from Napoleon to Al-Qaeda, 2003 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 9)
    - Book Review The New York Times Book Review, A Look Over My Shoulder: A Life in the Central Intelligence Agency, "Company Man", 2003 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 10)
    - Book Reviews, 1978-2000 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 11)
    - "Bridge to the Past", Sleepy Hollow Restorations, 1977 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 12)
    - Documentaries, Narration, 1998 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 13)
    - Edward R. Murrow and William J. Casey, Documentary Proposals, 1995 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 14)
    - Erie Canal, Research Material, 2000 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 15)
    - "The Flight of the Enola Gay"Modern Maturity, 1985 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 16)
    - The Fornix, ca. 1980 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 17)
    - The Fornix, ca. 1980 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 18)
    - "The Great Gun Merchant"American Heritage, 1974 August (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 19)
    - "How much Legal Protection does New York State give the Consumer?" Consumer Counsel to the Governor, 1958 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 20)
    - Influenza Epidemic of 1918, Persico Article and Documentary, 1996-1998 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 21)
    - "An Interview with John Huston"American Heritage, 1982 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 22)
    - "The Last Days of the Third Reich"American Heritage, 1985 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 23)
    - "The Making of a War Criminal".Dimensions, 1994 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 24)
    - Marilyn Monroe and Joe DiMaggio, Book Proposal, 1997 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous, ca. 1960s-1976 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 26)
    - Opinion Piece New York Times, "When Quotes Can't Be Trusted", 1997 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 27)
    - Opinion Piece The Wall Street Journal, "Deception is Part of the Art of War, But Shhhhh!", 2002 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 28)
    - Opinion Piece New York Times, "Can Words Change Meaning?", Undated (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 29)
    - Research Material, 1959; 1976 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 30)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Bellagio Study and Conference Center Residency, 1996-2002 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 31)
    - "Rockefeller in Retrospect"New York Archives, 2001 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 32)
    - "Too Much Crime...Too Little Justice", Report of the President's Advisory Board, National Institute of Justice, ca. 1980s (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 33)
    - Upset, Proposed Book about 1948 Truman-Dewey Presidential Election, Correspondence and Proposal, 1996-1997 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 34)
    - Upset, Proposed Book about 1948 Truman-Dewey Presidential Election, Research Material, ca. 1968-1999 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 35)
    - Upset, Proposed Book about 1948 Truman-Dewey Presidential Election, Research Material, ca. 1968-1999 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 36)
    - "War Crimes Trials", for The Reader's Companion to Military History, 1994-1996 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 37)
    - "We May Never Mate Again"Times Union, 1999 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 38)
    - "Who knows? Who cares? Forgotten Children in Foster Care", Report of the National Commission on Children in Need of Parents, 1979 (Box 45 (3-Speeches and Writings), Folder 39)
- Correspondence, 1960-2002; 4; 1 cubic foot
  Correspondence to and from Persico can be found throughout the collection. For example, references to Persico's publications will be found in both the general correspondence files and the subseries of specific publications. While some correspondence is clearly personal or professional, there is not always a clear separation between the author's personal and professional correspondents. Persico appears to have retained copies of much of his outgoing correspondence in the form of typed and handwritten letters and email messages. The author's notable correspondents include: director John Huston who Persico interviewed for an article in American Heritage; Pulitzer Prize-winning authors Michael Shaara (1983) and William Kennedy (1983); journalist Jim Lehrer (1986); Broadway and television director Edwin Sherin (1985); author Thomas Powers (1993); and Casey Murrow (1995, 1998) among others.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1960; 1983-1994 (Box 46 (4-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Janklow, Mort, Correspondence, 1978-1985 (Box 46 (4-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Huston, John, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 46 (4-Correspondence), Folder 3)